{
    "id": "0235f11899784affabfdaff1bee86c8a",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I ................................",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "won't go",
                "wouldn't go",
                "wouldn't have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she would be happy if she ................................ more money.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you leave now, you ............................... the bus.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will catch",
                "would catch",
                "could catch"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My mother told me that if I had passed the test, she ....................................... me a bike.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "would have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were rich, I ............................... more time on traveling.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will spend",
                "would spend",
                "would have spent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had come on time, he ................................... mad.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not go",
                "would not go",
                "would not have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had apologized, they ................................... any further actions against you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not take",
                "would not take",
                "would not have taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ................................ early, you could meet her.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "arrived",
                "had arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ................................ the money, I would have admitted it.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "take",
                "took",
                "had taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ............................... more politely, she would lend you her car.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "asked",
                "ask",
                "had asked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you love me, I .................................. you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will love",
                "would love",
                "would have loved"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ........................................... Spanish at university, she could work as a translator.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + v1 in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "learn",
                "learned",
                "had learned"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}